CAR HORNS BEEP
RHYTHMIC TURKISH RAP MUSIC PLAYS
FOGHORN BLARES
CAR HORNS BEEP
INDISTINCT CHATTER
Detective Suleyman?
Yes. Welcome to Istanbul.
Oh. Follow me. Follow me, please.
Come on, follow me.
Follow me, come with me.
No, that's... Come with me.
This way.
Inspector Ikmen sent you?
Oh, yes. Yes, he did, yes.
So you know him? Oh, yes. Very well.
He's a very good inspector.
Very good, very good.
Oh...
Where are my keys?
Nope.
Ah.
CHUCKLES
With my lollipop.
Oh, dear.
PLANE ROARS OVERHEAD
Please.
Yes.
UP-TEMPO SYNTH MUSIC PLAYS
CAR HORN BLARES
BRAKES SCREECH
So what brings you
to Istanbul, Detective?
IN TURKISH:
No, no, no, no.
English, please, English.
It's good practice for me.
A job - with the police.
Ah. Yeah, homicide.
Oh.
So...
You want?
No. No?
You worked with the world-famous
London Metropolitan Police.
Yeah, well, the Met
wasn't a good fit for me.
Wrong name, wrong skin,
wrong religion, take your pick.
Perhaps they didn't like you.
No, no, no, that's
not possible, is it?
A charming young man like yourself.
But there must be something else -
some other reason
to uproot your whole life.
I'm just here to try
and do some good.
Some good? Yeah.
Doing bad is bad.
Doing good is very good.
Well, some might say.
TURKISH POP MUSIC POUNDS
DISTANT SIRENS BLARE
Just one moment, please.
TURKISH FLUTE MUSIC PLAYS
WATER LAPS GENTLY
LOUD CHATTERING
DRIVER:
Excuse me! Huh?
I beseech you, just one minute.
THEY CONTINUE BARGAINING
Is that what I think it is?
Ah.
Ah, ah, ah... Whoa...
I'm arresting you
for possession of
a controlled substance.
Detective Suleyman,
what are you doing?
Argh!
PHONE RINGS
Inspector Ikmen speaking.
SUSPECT GRUNTS
You're kidding me.
INSPECTOR IKMEN:
SUSPECT:
ROCK GUITAR STRUMS
VOICE SINGS IN TURKISH
STEADY SYNTH BEAT PLAYS
DRUMS BUILD
ROCK GUITAR SOLO PLAYS
DISTANT CHATTERING
Look who's here.
Our man from London.
Oh, ha.
Detective Ayse Farsakoglu.
Detective Mehmet Suleyman.
It's nice to meet you.
Try to keep up. He's fast.
He already tried to arrest Emir.
DETECTIVE FARSAKOGLU CHUCKLES
Hello, mate. Lovely to meet you.
That's our resident
tech genius, Tarik.
We don't let him out much.
Welcome, man. And that's your desk.
Tarik, if you don't mind?
Ah, Chief Inspector. Bucar,
please meet our newest recruit.
Oh...
Detective Mehmet Suleyman.
Nice to meet you, sir.
It wasn't easy juggling the budget
for your transfer.
I hope you're worth it.
I'll do my best, sir.
My goodness. Budgets.
I'm so grateful all I have to do
is solve murders.
Speaking of which, I have to
catch up on some casework.
Yes... If you'll excuse me,
thank you.
Welcome. Thank you.
Huh. Oh.
Sir...
..what should I do?
Let's get you to your induction.
Yeah.
CAT MEOWS
What's with all the cats?
Oh, they're very important. Yeah.
They're working
the mouse crime division.
See you, man.
GUN CLICKS
You know how to use it, yeah?
Yeah. I've done the training.
Good.
CAR HORNS BEEP
DISTANT SIRENS BLARE
DISTANT CHATTERING
CAR HORN BEEPS LOUDER
What are you doing?
Going to my apartment.
No, you're not.
No. I can get a taxi. Give it to me,
give it to me. No, no, no, no.
A body has been found.
Ayse is already at the scene.
Get in the car.
Go.
CAR HORN BEEPS
FOGHORN BLARES
TENSE SYNTH PLAYS
LOW TURKISH FLUTE PLAYS
DISTANT SIRENS BLARE
So...
Her ID was in the bag.
INSPECTOR IKMEN PUFFS AIR OUT
She was at university
studying economics.
INSPECTOR IKMEN SIGHS
QUIETLY: His daughter is
the same age as her.
What about the phone?
It's smashed.
They're getting it to IT.
INSPECTOR IKMEN SIGHS
Ah.
Your Magwitch has arrived.
Your great benefactor.
Don't you read Dickens?
Not regularly. What a shame.
Selma. Inspector Ikmen.
I trust you're treating
our new recruit well.
I treat everyone well.
Well, it's nice to meet you in
person, Madam Prosecutor.
And thank you for
helping my transfer.
Of course. How are you finding it?
I know.
WHISPERING: Ikmen seems a bit
eccentric. Old-school, maybe.
But you're in good hands.
Well, shall we begin?
Yes, please.
Victim's name is Gozde Seren,
19 years old.
Obvious blunt-force trauma,
cause of death.
Say, less than 24 hours.
We haven't found
a murder weapon yet,
but the cemetery is
full of heavy rocks.
I think we can safely call this
a murder, wouldn't you say, Madam?
Yes.
This is older, possibly defensive,
protecting herself from an attack.
May I? Yeah.
A stick? Or a belt, maybe.
Have the family been informed?
KNOCKING ON DOOR
INSPECTOR IKMEN GREETS WOMAN
WOMAN SOBS
HUSBAND:
WOMAN CONTINUES SOBBING
HUSBAND SHUSHES GENTLY
Er, we need to
ask you some questions.
Detective, perhaps you should take
statements from
the neighbours first.
Let the news settle for a moment.
WOMAN CRIES
Sir.
Cahit Bey.
Mm-hm.
Mm.
Sir, don't mean to interrupt.
Not at all, Detective, not at all.
So? I spoke to a few
of the neighbours.
Mrs Karavelli at number 26
said she was home all evening,
didn't see or hear anything.
A young Canadian woman, number 24,
said she wasn't home all evening.
Canadian?
Is that her?
Yeah.
A moment of your time, Miss?
I'm late for work.
Oh, that's all right.
We can ride with you.
Did you know Gozde?
No, not really. Sorry.
What a shame.
Ah!
So, should I drop you off?
No, no, no. Where are you going?
To my office in Esenyurt.
What a coincidence.
That's where we are headed.
Yeah.
11 o'clock is a strange
time to start work.
Would you like us to
talk to your boss for you?
Familiarise them with
the government guidelines?
Look, I'm sorry,
you made me nervous.
Hmm.
I'm not going to work.
My goodness!
So, just a late night drive, then?
Oh.
Or were you trying to avoid us?
I won't be offended.
I have an explanation,
if you'd care to listen.
I think Gozde had a double life.
At home, she had to
please a strict father
but, outside, she was
someone different.
Naturally, she was
interested in you.
Someone foreign, exotic,
who had the freedom she craved.
So I think you did know her.
Well enough to bring
her a sweet gift
from a trip home to Canada.
Help us learn how she lived, miss,
so we might find out how she died.
She...
She liked me, I guess. I don't know.
We hung out.
Had coffee just a few times, talked.
What did you talk about?
Just girl stuff.
Maybe we should be having this
conversation down at the station.
An excellent suggestion, Detective.
No, no, no, please, I...
She asked me about applying
for a Canadian visa.
Any contacts I had, I...
I didn't know anything, I swear.
She was terrified of her father
finding out,
so I don't know if she actually
did anything about it, truly.
Hmm.
Please don't tell him.
Mmn.
Ah!
Forensics are at the Serens'.
So, what are we doing here?
Something equally important.
Ah!
This is Suleyman, the Englishman
I was telling you about.
Listen, lovely to meet you,
but I should be going.
I've just arrived,
got a lot of unpacking to do.
Nonsense, come here,
come here, please.
This is my daughter. Hi. Hi.
Baba?
Ha-ha-ha!
So, how far along are you?
You...your baby?
I'm not pregnant.
Are you mad? I have three already!
LAUGHTER
So, what brings you
to Istanbul, Mehmet?
Cetin says you were born here
but raised in the UK?
Yeah, who moves to this dump?
Yeah. Yeah, my mum
and I left when I was young,
but it's weird - even
though I grew up in England,
it never quite felt like home.
Perhaps that's why
you became a detective -
you have an objective eye.
Well, anyway, a few years ago,
Mum died and, yeah,
I started to feel a pull.
What about your dad?
Is he still alive?
Yeah, he is. He lives here.
Oh. He must be excited
to see you back home.
Our relationship's...complicated.
Well, Fatoscum, obviously
there is more to the story
than our friend is letting us know.
I agree. It's about a girl, I bet.
It's always about a girl.
Or about a boy, or about whomever.
I couldn't possibly say.
THEY SING HAPPY BIRTHDAY IN TURKISH
THEY WHOOP
LEYLA: Mehmet, hi, how's London?
Leyla, how are you?
How's Istanbul? I'm, uh, OK.
It's been a while.
Yeah. Miss you.
And I...
I never got the chance...
No, please don't.
I don't want to hear you
apologise. Not again.
OK, OK, I'm sorry.
Uh, you OK? What's going on?
Um, look, there's this story
I've been working on.
It's not ready to be
published or anything yet,
but it's, um, it's pretty dark.
What, crime stuff?
Yeah, yeah, but, uh,
this is a whole nother level.
Like, it's everywhere.
It's here, it's in Europe,
the US, Middle East.
And Mehmet...
..I keep learning the same lesson.
Trust no-one.
So where are we at
on Gozde's murder?
Just waiting to hear
back from the Canadian Embassy
about her visa application.
Meanwhile, her brother, Lokman -
his alibi checks out.
He was with a friend at Cevis Hostel
the night she died.
Still waiting on crime scene
forensics for the father's belt,
and we should have them
in the next few hours.
And where are we on the phone?
Uh, software is working on
cracking it.
So, what do you suggest we do?
I think I go back to work.
Let's go talk to the fiance. Yep.
PHONE RINGS
Ayse Farsakoglu?
Look at that.
We're a marvellously
well-oiled machine already.
Just heard back from the Embassy -
Gozde did apply for a Canadian visa,
but it was rejected.
It'll be interesting to hear
what the fiance makes of that.
I researched him last night.
And what did you find?
His ex-wife - the one who
died in an accident in Monaco...
Certainly seemed very irregular.
A lot of press.
And a substantial family inheritance
being passed on to him.
But let me tell you something -
the French authorities never
attempted a prosecution.
Would you believe that? Why not?
He's a rich and
powerful man, Detective.
Do you need me to draw
a diagram or something?
Ah, Mesut Bey.
Thank you very much for seeing us.
Welcome.
Ah, what a beautiful view.
Beautiful.
Yes.
So what do you need?
Information concerning the brutal
and violent murder of your fiance.
Yes, of course.
But such as?
Where were you on Tuesday night?
Really?
At the Ruya Saray, my new hotel,
getting it ready.
I was helping to paint it myself.
There's about 300 people
you can check this with.
If I may say, you don't seem
particularly emotional.
I have $100 million of
debt financing my hotel.
Thousands of livelihoods at stake.
I really can't allow
myself to just stop.
Gozde did not have a choice.
And I'm sorry about that.
Truly. But the last thing
I would ever do is hurt her.
And I can't think of
anyone else who would either.
Doesn't make sense.
Did you know Gozde had applied
for a Canadian residence visa?
When? Two months ago.
So it looks like she
was not too happy
with the direction
her life was going.
I was going to give her the world.
So, tell me, how does
a very busy man
such as yourself
find the time to meet
someone like Gozde?
Her father.
For months, he was chasing me.
"Mesut Bey, I have
a beautiful daughter."
Eventually I say,
"Fine, let me take a look.
"Give me your phone."
And to my surprise, he was right.
I knew he only wanted
to get close to me, but...
..who cares?
Gozde was everything.
And it worked too. I let her nobody
father supply
all the refrigeration units
for the Ruya Saray.
A million-dollar contract.
Look, you see,
that girl was Cahit Seren's
winning lottery ticket.
He knew about the visa.
There's no way he's
telling us everything.
No way. But, you know,
excellent work bringing it up.
What, you wanted to discuss weather?
We needed answers.
Uh-huh. You do that by first
building rapport and then you...
You don't build rapport with men
like that. Now, now, children!
Trying to listen to
a message from Forensics.
We need to find the Serens.
You just observe for now.
This is delicate.
I can be delicate.
Kemal?
I keep thinking about a pistachio
baklava my mother used to make.
Excuse me?
She made it on special occasions.
It took hours. I loved it.
I asked you about Kemal.
What took hours?
My mother's baklava.
Ooh, baked desserts. Love it!
She made it for her birthday, ninth.
I was a fat, greedy little boy
and I loved that baklava,
so in the middle of the night,
before our birthday,
I sneaked out of bed and ate it all.
I woke up Gozde,
guilty and panicked, and told her.
Next morning, she told
my father she'd done it.
My father knew she was lying,
but he couldn't prove it,
so she took the beating for me.
She really was special, you know.
Is that what Kemal thought?
Kemal's from Lebanon.
He and his mother came
and settled in Antep.
How did you meet?
Gaming, a few years ago.
And then his mother
died from a heart attack.
He had nothing.
He came to Istanbul looking for
work, go to night school maybe.
So I got him a job with Mesut.
That's how he met with Gozde.
Like everyone else,
he just fell in love.
When I found out they were fooling
around, I knew he was screwed.
Mesut was her way out
of our house, away from...
Kemal was who I went
to see the night Gozde...
I wanted to tell him to leave
her alone, stop texting.
I think she'd broken up with him.
Was he there?
No. Where was he?
I don't know.
I don't think I know him any more.
Why waste time?
You see my records?
Yeah, I know what I'm doing.
Where's Ayse?
Having a look around
Mesut's new hotel.
So you're with me,
where I can see you.
Interesting interview
technique, by the way.
Well, people communicate
with you all the time.
Revealing things about themselves.
Even when they think
they're concealing them.
Come along, let's find
our new friend, Kemal.
Well, between us and Mesut Calak,
it's no surprise
Kemal's disappeared.
TINKLING
Careless of him
to leave it behind. Mm-hm.
Teenagers, eh?
I thought you didn't waste time.
THEY PRAY
Just don't.
HE LAUGHS
Try one?
Was it a good run?
So where are we headed?
Vefa.
The Arab neighbourhood.
I have an intuition our young
friend needs some home comforts.
OK.
And what about you?
What are you doing?
Uh, just, you know,
looking for an actual lead.
Perhaps if you hadn't
let him evade your grasp?
Just looking at his Instagram.
Find something?
Sure did.
An internet cafe he visited.
Tremendous. Where abouts?
Vefa.
Really?
Thank you, Detective.
CALL TO PRAYER
It's in here. Mm.
All right.
Police!
This a customer of yours?
Don't bullshit me. He's wanted
in connection with a homicide.
And if you don't want me...
We're from Homicide,
and we're looking for someone.
We believe he used your equipment,
and as you can see,
the photo is time stamped. So can
you please look at your records
to see if he has been here
or not, hmm?
It's fine, all right?
We come back with a warrant
and we seize the computers.
And in the meantime, they delete
whatever they feel like.
So do you suggest we do?
We go door to door.
Do you have any idea
how big Vefa actually is?
OK, so let's get started, then.
PHONE BEEPS
I'll get you some patrol units.
Where are you going?
Well, I'm sure
it's a waste of effort,
but I'm going to pursue
a different avenue.
Mind your fingers.
CLASSICAL MUSIC
Mm.
Mesut Bey.
Mm-hm.
Detective Suleyman.
Still nothing, sorry.
Nobody's seen Kemal,
and we just got
the burglary called in, so...
CHILDREN SHOUT
BELL BUZZES
PHONE BUZZES
DOOR BUZZES
Leyla.
Mehmet! Hi!
Oh, my gosh, I'm so bored. Can we
please go out and do something?
Shoreditch, West End -
just anything, anywhere, please.
What's wrong?
Leyla, we...
We're in Istanbul.
LEYLA CHUCKLES
What? Shut up.
Mehmet, look.
Mehmet?
What's going on?
Mehmet, what's going on?
Tell me what's going on!
It's OK. It's not OK!
Stop, I-I don't understand.
What's happening?
I don't...
Tell me what's happening!
Don't worry.
The doctor says this is very normal
with head injuries.
Being with family, you being here -
it'll all help.
It's only a few months
since the accident.
Accident?
Do you think she's safe here?
She's my sister's daughter.
I protect her with my life.
Thank you for the money. It helps.
How long are you planning to stay?
As long as it takes.
I've transferred to Istanbul.
I have to find who did this to her.
Whoever did this,
she's no threat to them any more.
Let it lie.
She would have never left London
if it wasn't for me...
..and none of this
would have happened.
I need to fix this.
Whatever way I can.
I didn't respect you
at your business.
I'm new here. I don't know
how things work here. I'm sorry.
This is Gozde Seren.
She's 19 and she was murdered.
Kemal can lead us to her killer.
I'm asking you to help if you can.
I went back to the internet cafe.
They did some digging after we left
and found Kemal's browsing history.
Covered it up pretty well.
But they did find this.
A Snake Tor browser?
It's a high-level way
of accessing the dark web.
I mean, even just downloading
the browser
means usually you're into
some pretty shady stuff.
So what was he using this for?
Could be anything.
Drugs, credit card information,
fake papers.
An escape route?
Yeah.
Good work.
We are into Gozde's phone.
Let's go.
PHONE BUZZES
Ikmen.
The last message on Gozde's phone.
What?
Kemal called her to the graveyard?
Yes.
Go through the rest of the phone.
You come with me.
Where are you going?
EXCITED SCREAMING
DANCE MUSIC
I understand
you're looking for a boy in...
HE WHISPERS
Yes.
You're looking for a boy in Vefa
who might have taken something
that belonged to you.
But? I'm also looking for him.
So, when you find him,
I want you to bring
him to me instead.
And why would I do that?
Because it is something beyond money
or reputation
or anything you care about.
It's justice
for a life taken too soon.
That's your job, not mine.
True.
But I'd like you to imagine
your mother, your sister,
your daughter lying dead
in their own blood.
You and your business,
in this moment,
are totally insignificant to me.
All I care about is that poor girl,
finding out what happened to her.
And if I can, bringing peace
to those she was taken from.
And that boy will help.
That should be motivation enough.
But if it's not,
if you do not listen
to your better angels,
then you should know that I will not
stop coming for you. Ever.
I will dedicate my life
to your destruction,
however possible.
My name is Inspector Cetin Ikmen.
Ask about me.
I can be formidable.
LEYLA: Mehmet, I keep learning
the same lesson.
Trust no-one.
Are you in trouble?
Can I help?
Actually, you know what? Um...
I, er, I shouldn't have called.
Leyla. No, I'm sorry.
I'm fine, really.
Um, you take care. OK?
PEOPLE SHRIEK
That's it? Seriously?
OUTER DOOR OPENS
You're still here. Mm-hm.
Yeah, we went through the phone,
and there's a write-up
on Ikmen's desk.
OK.
Go get some sleep.
You find him?
Who?
How did you do this?
MUSIC: Suspus
by Ceza